

### PANKAJ KUMAR BAJAJ

Contact: +977 9801018285/+918481969251, Email: pankajbajaj23@gmail.com, Skype ID – pankaj.bajaj930

Aims to pursue challenging assignments with a reputed organization

#### **SYNOPSIS**

A Chartered Accountant with experience in varied industries (Manufacturing, FMCG, Logistics, NBFCs, Service). Experience includes understanding of the entity's business and its industry and environment, its accounting policies and practices, its financial performance, developing and understanding strong analytical & organizational abilities in response to those risks and planning approach towards significant risks, with adeptness in preparing accounting records, financial statements and MIS.

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

#### Since May 2013:

Working with **Dabur Nepal Pvt Ltd.** The task involves:

- Preparing Vision (4 year strategic plan) / Annual Operative Plan / Quarterly Business Review decks for CFO
- Monthly Detailed Analysis on overall profitability for Nepal along with detailed comparison by Business Divisions
- Aligning cross functional stakeholders for overall profitability during Vision / AOP financials rollup
- Support the Country Manager / CFO on various pricing decision by analyzing Contribution at various Price points
- Responsible for Overall planning / Forecasting of Operating Cash flow for the Business
- Responsible for Transfer Pricing of Company Exports
- Responsible for analyzing the contribution of NPDs along with comparison with competition
- Responsible for working capital management, payroll processing and payables accounting
- Reviewing internal control systems, identifying weaknesses in key control areas and presenting methods for Procedural Improvements
- Ensure IT to support business initiatives Enivesh migration/ online claim process of distributors
- Co-ordinating with Statutory Auditors & Internal Auditors and ensured smooth functioning of the audit process.

# November 2009 to May 2013:

Worked with Idea Cellular Ltd. The task involves:

- MIS reporting and budgetary controls of East Service Area.
- Preparation of Annual Operating Plan through Hyperion Tool.
- Actively participated in the IFRS implementation team.
- Carrying out extensive Product analysis to enhance revenue and ensure cost efficiency which boost business growth

### November 2008 to October 2009:

Worked with Vedanta Aluminium Ltd. The task involves:

- Preparation and circulation of Project Expenditure Report vis-à-vis the budgeted amounts
- Maintaining complete control over various Borrowings of the company which includes Debentures, ECBs,
   INR Loans, its accounting & ensuring timely payment of interest due.
- Forecasting Forex Cash Flows for fresh forex bookings and rollovers, Forex MTM statement for open exposure, Hedge Documentation in accordance with AS 30.
- Ensure accounting of investment activities of the company.



Acting as a core team member for preparation and Consolidation of Financial Statements.

### February 2008 to October 2008:

Industrial Trainee with the Investment Subsidiaries of ITC Limited (a consortium of 14 companies). A few of these companies are 100% subsidiaries of ITC Limited and even have their own subsidiaries and step subsidiaries (Indian as well as foreign), Joint Ventures and Associates. The important areas handled as a part of various assignments are:

- Consolidation of Accounts of Investment subsidiaries and prepare FFC Accounts for all companies. Helped
  the accounting team in successfully integrating the accounts of the foreign subsidiary, which was acquired
  during the year, as per its laid down accounting policies.
- Computation of tax provisions, filing of returns, payment of advance taxes, and reconciliation of accounts post tax assessments. Ensure that the Tax Returns and related tax payments are being correctly filed on time.
- Ensured compliance with RBI Prudential Norms relating to accounting, Fair Practice Code, Know Your
  Customer Policy, Investment & Loan Policies. Prepared and filed the monthly, half yearly & annual returns
  and the returns under Prevention of Money Laundering Act to RBI for the investment associates.

### October 2005 to January 2008:

Articleship with **Damle Dhandhania & Co.**, Kolkata. Successfully carried out statutory and tax audits, specific purpose engagements, agreed upon procedures of MNCs, listed Companies, Trusts, and other private sector companies.

#### ACADEMIC CREDENTIALS

Year	Examination	Institution	Marks Secured
Nov, 2007	CA (Final)	ICAI	53.88% (1st Attempt)
May, 2005	CA (PE II)	ICAI	53.67% (1 <sup>st</sup> Attempt)
May, 2004	CA (PE I)	ICAI	72.75% (1st Attempt with <b>DISTINCTION</b> )
2006	B.Com (H)	Umeshchandra College, Kolkata	64.00%
2003	XII (W.B.C.H.S.E.)	Shree Jain Vidyalaya, Kolkata	69.40%
2001	X (I.C.S.E.)	Saint Thomas School, Godda	88.00%

# COMPUTER PROFICIENCY

- MS Office, Internet Applications and various Windows Applications.
- Working knowledge of Tally, SAP, BW, Oracle, and Hyperion.
- Have worked effectively in customized software of various clients during the audit stint.

## **OTHER INTERESTS**

- Active participant in sports at school and hostel.
- Participated in Debate Competition at District level.
- Received Idea Excellence Award.
- Led Annual Social Committee which organized Sangam' 2006 an annual Hostel Event. The task included Event Management, Fund collection and designing of Souvenirs.
- Active Participation in Help Age India Programme.
- Worked as a Financial Advisor at MetLife India.